<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: R | A Coding Monkey's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://jchain.github.io/blog/categories/r/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jchain.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-04T15:40:26-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://jchain.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zandy]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Install RcppOctave if Octave is in user-defined directory]]></title>
    <link href="http://jchain.github.io/blog/2013/01/28/install-rcppoctave-if-octave/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-28T23:43:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jchain.github.io/blog/2013/01/28/install-rcppoctave-if-octave</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Even though I have been very busy these days I think I should try to get at least one post published per month. My recent job involved a lot of data analysis and statistical computing. I pushed myself to get familiar with <a href="http://www.r-project.org">R</a> because some packages from R are indispensable for my work. Meanwhile I also wanted to reuse my existing <a href="http://www.octave.org">Octave</a> code. Luckily I get the best of both worlds by using <a href="http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/RcppOctave/">RcppOctave</a> which is a bridging package connecting the R and Octave sessions.</p>
<p>I compiled the latest Octave on the server and installed in my home directory. When installing <code>RcppOctave</code> in R by running</p>
<pre><code>install.packages(&#39;RcppOctave&#39;) </code></pre>
<p>I ran into an error message like this:</p>
<pre><code>** preparing package for lazy loading
Creating a generic function for ‘show’ from ‘methods’ in package ‘RcppOctave’
    (from the saved implicit definition)
** help
Error : /tmp/Rtmp028JZY/R.INSTALL6dea26e533ee/RcppOctave/man/o_addpath.Rd:40: unable to load
shared object &#39;/home/zandy/lib64/R/library/RcppOctave/libs/RcppOctave.so&#39;:
liboctinterp.so.1: cannot open shared object file: No such file or directory

ERROR: installing Rd objects failed for package ‘RcppOctave’
* removing ‘/home/zandy/lib64/R/library/RcppOctave’</code></pre>
<p>The build phase seemed OK. Only did the install phase complain. I spent some time and figured out a work-around is to specify the library path to your <code>liboctinterp.so</code>:</p>
<pre><code>export LD_LIBRARY_PATH=$LD_LIBRARY_PATH:$HOME/lib64/octave/3.6.3</code></pre>
<p>I don’t know much about the internal mechanism of <code>install.packages</code> otherwise I may be able to fix the problem completely.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
