<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: GNOME | A Coding Monkey's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://zandyware.com/blog/categories/gnome/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zandyware.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-17T02:36:20-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://zandyware.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zandy]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nomachine and GNOME Redraw Problem]]></title>
    <link href="http://zandyware.com/blog/2012/11/16/nomachine-and-gnome-redraw-problem/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-16T15:36:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://zandyware.com/blog/2012/11/16/nomachine-and-gnome-redraw-problem</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I use <a href="http://www.nomachine.com">Nomachine</a> a lot when I work from home. My home and work Linux desktop are both running
GNOME 3. There were a problem disturbing me for a while. Everything works fine at workplace probably
due to the supper fast local internet connection. But when I connected to the remote desktop via
Nomachine, the GUIs of remote applications were very lagging and the redraws seemed out of sync
leaving blanks here and there. I've tried many ways to improve that, including upgrading the ISP
bandwidth, trying the latest NoMachine 4 Preview, tuning the various options in the settings. But
all efforts were vain. Until one day I aimlessly chose KDE in NoMachine and the redraw issue were
gone. Every GUI programs ran perfectly in KDE, both GTK+ ones and non-GTK+ ones.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to show GNOME top panel from keyboard?]]></title>
    <link href="http://zandyware.com/blog/2012/08/19/how-to-show-gnome-top-panel-from-keyboard/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-19T02:06:46-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zandyware.com/blog/2012/08/19/how-to-show-gnome-top-panel-from-keyboard</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My computer display is not big so I have tried ways to save my screen real-estate. It looks to me that the designers of GNOME 3 must have a huge display.  The default window title bar are too high in my view. Besides the top panel is thicker than that in Unity. To make my life easier, I first installed the GTK+ 3.x theme from <a href="http://www.gnome-look.org">gnome-look.org</a> to reduce the height of the title bar. Then I set the top panel of GNOME desktop to 'auto hide'. But whenever I want to look at the weather or the time I have to move mouse over it to make it show. This is tedious. I searched online for a shortcut to show it. Many of results are prior to GNOME 3. Besides, I don't like the methods to change the 'gsetting' or 'gconf'.</p>

<p>It turns out that the simplest way to to hit 'Alt+F1' to activate the 'Application' in the top panel and hit 'Esc' to hide it again. So simple.</p>

<p>BTW: I'm using the fallback of GNOME 3.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My favorite Gnome terminal font is fixedsys-excelsior]]></title>
    <link href="http://zandyware.com/blog/2011/08/04/my-favorite-gnome-terminal-font-is-fixedsys-excelsior/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-04T23:57:39-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zandyware.com/blog/2011/08/04/my-favorite-gnome-terminal-font-is-fixedsys-excelsior</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Finding a good monospaced font for Gnome terminal was used to be my big wish. I have tried bitstream
mono, droid sans mono, inconsola. None of them was satisfactory in Gnome terminal with dark
background(much better in white background but I don't like white background). Finally, my heart has
been settled down with <a href="http://www.fixedsysexcelsior.com/">fixedsys-excelsior</a>. It just looks very
comfortable with my black background.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Built gtk3.0 on openSUSE-11.1]]></title>
    <link href="http://zandyware.com/blog/2011/03/03/built-gtk3-0-on-opensuse-11-1/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-03T01:48:26-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://zandyware.com/blog/2011/03/03/built-gtk3-0-on-opensuse-11-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I built gtk3.0 from source on openSUSE-11.1 x86-64bit. As expected, I ran into one annoying problem like this:</p>

<blockquote><p>symbol lookup error: /opt/gnome/lib/libcairo-gobject.so.2: undefined symbol: cairo_region_destroy</p></blockquote>

<p>I searched for the solution online. Someone suggested disabling gobject-introspection when compiling gtk3. But the default setting for gtk3 is indeed without gobject-introspection support. I got stuck and very confused. Finally, I got the things done by compiling the latest gobject-introspection(0.10.x) and enabling gobject-introspection support for atk, gdk-pixbuf and any other dependency libraries which could be set to enable this feature. YMMV. Here is the screenshot showing the about dialog from gtk3-demo.</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_147" align="aligncenter" width="432" caption="gtk3-demo"]<a href="http://zandyware.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/gtk3-demo.png"><img src="http://zandyware.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/gtk3-demo.png" alt="gtk3-demo" /></a>[/caption]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
