<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Linux | A Coding Monkey's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://zandyware.com/blog/categories/linux/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zandyware.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-09T20:18:42-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://zandyware.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zandy]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quickly look up a word or phrase from commandline]]></title>
    <link href="http://zandyware.com/blog/2012/09/28/quickly-look-up-a-word-or-phrase-from-commandline/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-28T14:46:55-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zandyware.com/blog/2012/09/28/quickly-look-up-a-word-or-phrase-from-commandline</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wrote two very short Bash functions to help me quickly look up a word or phrase using
<a href="http://elinks.or.cz/">elinks</a>. You can use w3m as you wish but elinks shows a better layout in my
eyes.</p>

<p>```bash</p>

<h1>look up on urbandictionary.com</h1>

<p>ub () {
 a=$@
 elinks www.urbandictionary.com/${a// /%20}
}</p>

<h1>look up on thefreedictionary.com</h1>

<p>fd () {
 a=$@
 elinks www.thefreedictionary.com/${a// /+}
}
```</p>

<p>Usage:</p>

<pre><code>ub your_word
fd your_word
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MC (Midnight-Commander) 4.8.5 is slow, try 4.8.6]]></title>
    <link href="http://zandyware.com/blog/2012/09/27/mc-midnight-commander-4-8-5-is-slow-try-4-8-6/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-27T23:57:17-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zandyware.com/blog/2012/09/27/mc-midnight-commander-4-8-5-is-slow-try-4-8-6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently MC was upgraded from 4.7.x to 4.8.5 on my 32bit Fedora 17. The start-up time was totally
unbearable, around 15 sec to start. I compiled the latest release v4.8.6 and that time dropped to
the negligible (&lt; 1sec).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to show GNOME top panel from keyboard?]]></title>
    <link href="http://zandyware.com/blog/2012/08/19/how-to-show-gnome-top-panel-from-keyboard/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-19T02:06:46-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zandyware.com/blog/2012/08/19/how-to-show-gnome-top-panel-from-keyboard</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My computer display is not big so I have tried ways to save my screen real-estate. It looks to me that the designers of GNOME 3 must have a huge display.  The default window title bar are too high in my view. Besides the top panel is thicker than that in Unity. To make my life easier, I first installed the GTK+ 3.x theme from <a href="http://www.gnome-look.org">gnome-look.org</a> to reduce the height of the title bar. Then I set the top panel of GNOME desktop to 'auto hide'. But whenever I want to look at the weather or the time I have to move mouse over it to make it show. This is tedious. I searched online for a shortcut to show it. Many of results are prior to GNOME 3. Besides, I don't like the methods to change the 'gsetting' or 'gconf'.</p>

<p>It turns out that the simplest way to to hit 'Alt+F1' to activate the 'Application' in the top panel and hit 'Esc' to hide it again. So simple.</p>

<p>BTW: I'm using the fallback of GNOME 3.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fix the broken Bash file and directory name completion on Ubuntu Linux]]></title>
    <link href="http://zandyware.com/blog/2012/06/02/fix-the-broken-bash-file-and-directory-name-completion-on-ubuntu-linux/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-02T17:12:54-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zandyware.com/blog/2012/06/02/fix-the-broken-bash-file-and-directory-name-completion-on-ubuntu-linux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I didn't remember ever since when my Bash filename and directory name completion functioned wackily. Everytime I hit 'tab' to complete a directory name, Bash didn't append the backslash nor printed out candidates (just like what it described like <a href="http://ubuntuforums.org/showthread.php?t=1053832">here</a> and <a href="http://timlabath.com/words/2011/05/10/ubuntu-11-04-and-broken-bash-completion/">here</a>). It drove me banana. Meanwhile, my Bash worked very well under other Linux distributions (openSUSE, CentOS). The culprit was the a Bash completion file for adobe acrobat reader under /etc/bash_completion.d/. Delete it and the problem will be solved.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Switch your Linux laptop display to a projector]]></title>
    <link href="http://zandyware.com/blog/2012/05/03/switch-your-linux-laptop-display-to-a-projector/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-03T22:45:31-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://zandyware.com/blog/2012/05/03/switch-your-linux-laptop-display-to-a-projector</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In a job interview two months ago, no matter how hard I tried I simply couldn't export the screen of my laptop running Ubuntu Linux to a projector. It was the first time that I linked a Linux computer to a projector. Luckily the interviewers were generous enough and the four people of us sat together tightly to watch the slides on my 15" laptop screen. They gave me a job offer in the end but I just hoped that I could have done a better presentation that day.</p>

<p>I searched for a solution for that on the web. It seemed a headache for many Linux users. Finally I ran into <a href="http://willem.engen.nl/projects/disper/">Disper</a>. It solved my problem perfectly.</p>

<p>Read on how to do it in more details <a href="http://www.baibhav.com.np/article/6-computer-tips-a-tricks/32-projector-external-monitor-display-problem-on-ubuntu-1110-solved-.html">here</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
